Guide to the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Office of the Dean records, 1960-1997, bulk 1983-1994
New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Office of the Dean records, 1960-1997, bulk 1983-1994
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Office of the Dean records, 1960-1997, bulk 1983-1994
24-01-3381
New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Office of the Dean
5 cubic ft.
Subject files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence and subject files compiled by the Office of the Dean of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine during Robert D. Phemister's tenure as dean.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Robert D. Phemister was Dean of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine from 1985-1995.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence and subject files compiled by the Office of the Dean of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine during Robert D. Phemister's tenure as dean.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Phemister, Robert D.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine.
Subjects:
Veterinary medicine--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
In original order.
CONTAINER LIST
- Deceased Emeriti, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Donald W. Baker, 1967-1978, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Emmett Bergman, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Cyril Comar, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Gordon Danks, 1977-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- D.D. Delahanty, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- H.H. Dukes, 1962-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Myron Fincher, 1965-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- J.C. Geary, 1976-1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Herbert L. Gilman, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ellis P. Leonard, 1969-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Philip P. Levine, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Peter Olafson, 1965-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Charles Rickard, 1985-1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Hadley Stephenson, 1965-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- John Whitlock, 1979-1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- College Vital Facts/Statistics, ca. 1980s (Box 1, Folder 17)
- History, Veterinary Medicine, ca 1960-1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Leonard - History of the College, ca. 1970s (Box 1, Folder 19)
- College History, ca. 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Jacob Gould Schurman, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Centennial
  - Book, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Poster Session, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Celebration, 21 March 1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Committee, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Budget, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Background Material, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Miscellaneous, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Cornell Veterinarian, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Cornell Veterinarian, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Cornell Veterinarian, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Cornell Veterinarian, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Dean's Messages, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Dean Phemister's Resignation, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- College Advisory Council, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- College Advisory Council, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- College Advisory Council, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- College Advisory Council, May 1-2, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- College Advisory Council - Agendas, Minutes and Reports, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- College Advisory Council - Appointment Letters, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- College Advisory Council - Membership and Terms, 1987-1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- College Advisory Council - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Legislation - Dog Licensing - Mandatory Census, 1978-1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Requested Legislative Additions to 1994-1995 Budget, Feb 4, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- "Report on Financial Trends for the Statutory Colleges in Relation to the Endowed Colleges", 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Cost of Education, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- SUNY Budget Reduction, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Provost Budget conference, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Provost Planning Conference, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Provost Planning Meeting - Dept. Submission, Nov. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Report to the Provost, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Report to the Provost - Dept. Reports, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Report to the Provost - Backup, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Academic Plan, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Cornell Corporate Contracts, Grants and Gifts Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Cornell Contracts and Grant Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Cornell Gift Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Planning Report, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Precinct and Project Planning, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Precinct and Project Planning, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Generic Impact Statement, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Facilities
  - Facilities Projects - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Facilities Projects - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Facilities Projects - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Master Plan - Staffing Formulae, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Surge Space, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Animal Inventory, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Feline SPF Building, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Marmota, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Space Inventory, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Master Plan - General Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Master Plan - General Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Davis, Brody & Assoc and Russo & Sonder, 1989-1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Master Plan - Construction, 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Project Request - Facilities Master Plan, Oct 13, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Central Planning Committee, 1987-1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Central Planning Committee Minutes, 1987-1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Construction Newsletters and Alerts, 1987-1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Space - Allocation and Reallocation of Space, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Space Allocations Memo Addressed Faculty, May 15, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Academic Deans/Provost Conference - Thornfield, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Academic Deans/Provost Retreat - Thornfield, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Academic Deans/Provost Retreat - Oneida Lake, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Deans Council, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Deans Council, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Statutory Deans Meetings, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Statutory Deans Meetings, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Statutory Deans Meetings, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Statutory Deans Meetings, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Statutory Deans Meetings, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Tower Club Reception/Dinner, May 19, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Tower Club Dinner, May 13, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Cornell Trustees/Council Annual Meeting, Oct 22-24, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Cornell Trustees/Council Annual Meeting, Oct 16-18, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Cornell Trustees/Council Annual Meeting, Oct 10-12, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- University Faculty, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Committee on use of Animals in Teaching, 1983-1990 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Committee to Examine Equine Programs, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Breeders Cup - Aqueduct, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Cornell Days at Goshen Harness Track, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Cornell Days at Belmont, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Equine Program Executive Committee, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Equine Practitioners Workshop, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Proposal - "Equine Referral Clinic on Long Island", 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Proposal - Revision of Hospital Emergency Service, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Low Temperature Biology - Task Force Report, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Rare Germplasm Repository, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Canine Symposium, 1985, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Regional Small Animal Symposium, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Laser Scanning Confocal Microscope Proposal, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Laboratory of Equine Embryo Biology, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Pew Charitable Trusts
  - Phase I, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Greensboro Breakfast Group, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Academic Planning Committee/Faculty Retreat May, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Academic Planning Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Penn-Cornell-Tufts Representatives, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Proposal - Northeast Consortium, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Phase III, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Phase III Final Report, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Phase IV, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Meeting With Ed O'Neil, Boston Airport, Aug 1990 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Health Professionals Advisory Panels, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Higher Education Roundtable, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Leadership and Teambuilding Workshop, Sept 1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - National Veterinary Strategic Education Task Force - AACMC, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Project - "Attitudes and Perception of Minorities towards Veterinary Medicine", 1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Quarterly and Interim Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Workshops, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990-1992, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Hanover, Germany - Dr. Kaaden, ca. 1989-1997 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- University of Parana, Brazil, 1988-1993 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- China, 1983-1992 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Portugal - Prof F.J. Tikal Viegas, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Chufalongkorn University - Thailand, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Argentina/Cornell, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Professor Kalmen Perk - Israel, 1978-1994 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Academic Scholars Program for Vet Students, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Doctoral Program Reviews, 1988-1994 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Graduate Studies Retreat & Survey, 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Annual Faculty Picnic, 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Miscellaneous, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  Includes vintage stationary of Anton Dill & Son, Practical Horseshoer, given to Dean Phemister. Also a brochure, circa 1970, on the Tierärztliche Hochschule Hannover, (University of Veterinary Medicine Hanover)
- Print of Dr. James Law (Box 4)
- Central Planning Committee (VMC), ca. 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Central Planning Committee (VMC), ca. 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Diagnostic Lab Renovation, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Diagnostic Lab Renovation, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Report for Accreditation by the American Association of Laboratory Diagnosticians, Dec 12-13, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Facility Program, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 6)
- "Facility Master Plan" by Davis, Brody,etc, 30 Aug 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Facility Program and Secondary Teaching Center, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Accreditation - Self Evaluation Report, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Accreditation - Self Evaluation Report, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Accreditation - Appendices - Self Evaluation Report, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Accreditation - Professional Courses, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Transgenic Animal Center, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- College Executive Committee Retreat, 18 June 1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Search Committee for New Dean, ca. 1983 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Annual Reports to the President, 1965-1990 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Announcements, vol. 79, no. 5, July 30, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)